<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>The Archives Unleashed Toolkit on The Archives Unleashed Project</title>
    <link>https://archivesunleashed.org/aut/</link>
    <description>Recent content in The Archives Unleashed Toolkit on The Archives Unleashed Project</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 09 Mar 2016 19:56:50 +0100</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://archivesunleashed.org/aut/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>The Archives Unleashed Toolkit</title>
      <link>https://archivesunleashed.org/aut/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Mar 2016 19:56:50 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://archivesunleashed.org/aut/</guid>
      <description>Introduction Internet Archive servers in San Francisco, photo by Ian Milligan.
The Archives Unleashed Toolkit is an open-source platform for managing web archives built on Hadoop. The platform provides a flexible data model for storing and managing raw content as well as metadata and extracted knowledge. Tight integration with Hadoop provides powerful tools for analytics and data processing via Spark.
Most of this documentation is built on resilient distributed datasets (RDD).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hands on With The Archives Unleashed Toolkit</title>
      <link>https://archivesunleashed.org/aut/docker-install/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Sep 2018 11:51:41 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://archivesunleashed.org/aut/docker-install/</guid>
      <description>This quick guide will walk through how to install Docker for Mac users. Much of this is also applicable to Windows users, although the screenshots are from a Mac.
Resources  Docker Community Edition for Mac Docker Community Edition for Windows  Install Docker To install Docker for a Mac OS, use this link. You can also use these instructions to install Docker on a Windows 10 Professional installation, by using this link.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hands on With The Archives Unleashed Toolkit</title>
      <link>https://archivesunleashed.org/aut/lesson/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 May 2018 11:51:41 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://archivesunleashed.org/aut/lesson/</guid>
      <description>Welcome to the Archives Unleashed Toolkit hands-on walkthrough!
The reality of any hands-on workshop is that things will break. We&amp;rsquo;ve tried our best to provide a robust environment that can let you walk through the basics of the Archives Unleashed Toolkit alongside us.
If you have any questions, let Nick Ruest or Ian Milligan know.
Table of Contents  Installation and Use Hello World: Our First Script Extracting Some Text  Ouch!</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>