<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>The Archives Unleashed Toolkit on The Archives Unleashed Project</title>
    <link>https://archivesunleashed.org/aut/</link>
    <description>Recent content in The Archives Unleashed Toolkit on The Archives Unleashed Project</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 09 Mar 2016 19:56:50 +0100</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://archivesunleashed.org/aut/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>The Archives Unleashed Toolkit</title>
      <link>https://archivesunleashed.org/aut/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Mar 2016 19:56:50 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://archivesunleashed.org/aut/</guid>
      <description>The Archives Unleashed Toolkit is an open-source platform for analyzing web archives built on Apache Spark, which provides powerful tools for analytics and data processing.
You can process your data with either resilient distributed datasets (RDD) or [DataFrames.
Check out the code on GitHub along with helpful user documentation to get you started using the Archives Unleashed Toolkit. If you want hack on the Archives Unleashed Toolkit, check out our API documentation.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Digging into WARCs - Hands-On with the Archives Unleashed Toolkit</title>
      <link>https://archivesunleashed.org/aut/resaw/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 May 2019 11:51:41 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://archivesunleashed.org/aut/resaw/</guid>
      <description>Workshop Description Welcome to &amp;ldquo;Digging into WARCs: Hands-On with the Archives Unleashed Toolkit.&amp;rdquo; The Archives Unleashed Toolkit, or AUT, is an open-source platform for managing and analyzing web archives built on Apache Spark.
This is a hands-on introductory workshop with the Archives Unleashed Toolkit and Archives Unleashed Jupyter Notebooks. No existing technical knowledge is needed, and we will be aiming this at beginner and intermediate users alike.
This workshop is being held on Tuesday, June 18th from 14:00-17:30 in room BG2 0.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Archives Unleashed Datathon Cheat Sheet</title>
      <link>https://archivesunleashed.org/aut/datathon/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Jan 2019 11:51:41 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://archivesunleashed.org/aut/datathon/</guid>
      <description>This guide is meant to be a quick reference guide for attendees at the Archives Unleashed datathons. These are commonly-asked questions and options that attendees have used, and may be updated during events.
Screenshots are from Mac, as we don&amp;rsquo;t have a Windows machine on our project team. Our apologies.
Finding Your Terminal While the Archives Unleashed Cloud is easy to use in a web browser, the Archives Unleashed Toolkit requires the use of the command line.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>