<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Welcome to the Archives Unleashed Project on The Archives Unleashed Project</title>
    <link>https://archivesunleashed.org/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Welcome to the Archives Unleashed Project on The Archives Unleashed Project</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 08 Mar 2016 21:07:13 +0100</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://archivesunleashed.org/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>About the Archives Unleashed Project</title>
      <link>https://archivesunleashed.org/about-project/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Mar 2016 00:11:02 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://archivesunleashed.org/about-project/</guid>
      <description>Archives Unleashed aims to make petabytes of historical internet content accessible to scholars and others interested in researching the recent past. Supported by a grant from the Andrew W. Mellon Foundation, we are developing web archive search and data analysis tools to enable scholars, librarians and archivists to access, share, and investigate recent history since the early days of the World Wide Web.
Growing out of a series of datathons held at the University of Toronto, Library of Congress, Internet Archive, and the British Library, our team recognized the need for better analytics tools, community infrastructure, and accessible web archival interfaces.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Getting Started</title>
      <link>https://archivesunleashed.org/getting-started/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 May 2019 09:21:11 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://archivesunleashed.org/getting-started/</guid>
      <description>Overview The Archives Unleashed Project consists of four major tools: the Archives Unleashed Cloud, the Archives Unleashed Toolkit, the Archives Unleashed Jupyter Notebooks and Warclight.
   Tool Skill What it Does What You Need Ideal For      Beginner The Archives Unleashed Cloud is a web-based platform for working with Archive-It collections. Drawing on your Archive-It credentials, you can sync your collections, run basic analyses, and generate a standardized set of research derivatives: full text, network diagrams, and basic statistics on your collection.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Archives Unleashed Cloud</title>
      <link>https://archivesunleashed.org/cloud/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Mar 2016 19:56:50 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://archivesunleashed.org/cloud/</guid>
      <description>Introduction Imagine a world where you could access and analyze a web archives file in as few as three clicks, with no coding necessary. Oh wait, there&amp;rsquo;s a portal for that: the Archives Unleashed Cloud.
The Archives Unleashed Cloud is an open source cloud-based analysis tool that helps researchers and scholars conduct web archive analysis. It supports the priorities of accessibility and usability of web archives by providing users a web-based front end to access the Archives Unleashed Toolkit.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Archives Unleashed Toolkit</title>
      <link>https://archivesunleashed.org/aut/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Mar 2016 19:56:50 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://archivesunleashed.org/aut/</guid>
      <description>Introduction Internet Archive servers in San Francisco, photo by Ian Milligan.
The Archives Unleashed Toolkit is an open-source platform for managing web archives built on Hadoop. The platform provides a flexible data model for storing and managing raw content as well as metadata and extracted knowledge. Tight integration with Hadoop provides powerful tools for analytics and data processing via Spark.
Most of this documentation is built on resilient distributed datasets (RDD).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Archives Unleashed Jupyter Notebooks</title>
      <link>https://archivesunleashed.org/notebooks/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Nov 2017 09:21:11 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://archivesunleashed.org/notebooks/</guid>
      <description>Introduction We are excited to introduce our Archives Unleashed Jupyter Notebooks, a prototype method for working with the derivatives generated by the Archives Unleashed Cloud. They allow you to interactively explore and filter the domain count information, extracted full text, and network visualization data generated by the Cloud.
We are currently exploring greater integration between the notebooks and the Archives Unleashed Cloud.
To use them now, please visit the GitHub repository here and follow the instructions.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Warclight</title>
      <link>https://archivesunleashed.org/warclight/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Nov 2017 09:21:11 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://archivesunleashed.org/warclight/</guid>
      <description>Warclight is a Project Blacklight based Rails engine that supports the discovery of web archives held in the WARC and ARC formats. It allows faceted full-text search, record view, and other advanced discovery options. Warclight is designed to work with web archive data that is indexed via the UK Web Archive&amp;rsquo;s webarchive-discovery project.
You can visit our demo site here, or check out the code on GitHub along with documetation to get you started on your own Warclight application.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Get Involved</title>
      <link>https://archivesunleashed.org/get-involved/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Mar 2016 20:08:11 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://archivesunleashed.org/get-involved/</guid>
      <description>There are many ways you can participate in the Archives Unleashed Project.
          We have held three datathons since April 2018, with one more planned. Please stay tuned for future Calls for Participation on our events page.    If you would like to contribute code or help with the development of the Archives Unleashed Cloud or Toolkit. Visit our GitHub organization and repositories, open issues, submit pull requests, or make any suggestion in our Slack group.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Events</title>
      <link>https://archivesunleashed.org/events/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Mar 2016 20:10:46 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://archivesunleashed.org/events/</guid>
      <description>Upcoming Events The Archives Unleashed team will be hosting the final datathon in the spring of 2020. Will we post information here and through our channels as it becomes available. Feel free to explore past event pages to learn more about the datathon set up and checkout group projects.
   Date Location     April 26-27, 2018 Toronto, ON   November 1-2, 2018 Vancouver, BC   March 21-22, 2019 Washington, DC   Spring 2020 United States West Coast    Past Datathons We have had the pleasure of hosting several datathons.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Vancouver Datathon</title>
      <link>https://archivesunleashed.org/vancouver/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Dec 2017 15:20:57 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://archivesunleashed.org/vancouver/</guid>
      <description>About The World Wide Web has had a profound impact on how we research and understand the past. The sheer amount of cultural information that is generated and, crucially, preserved every day in electronic form, presents exciting new opportunities for researchers. Much of this information is captured within web archives.
The project team invites archivists, researchers (from the humanities, social sciences, and beyond), librarians, computer scientists, and web archiving enthusiasts to join us over the course of two days to collaboratively work with web collections and explore cutting-edge research tools through hands-on experience.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Washington, DC Datathon</title>
      <link>https://archivesunleashed.org/washington/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Dec 2017 15:20:57 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://archivesunleashed.org/washington/</guid>
      <description>About The World Wide Web has had a profound impact on how we research and understand the past. The sheer amount of cultural information that is generated and, crucially, preserved every day in electronic form, presents exciting new opportunities for researchers. Much of this information is captured within web archives.
The project team invites archivists, researchers (from the humanities, social sciences, and beyond), librarians, computer scientists, and web archiving enthusiasts to join us over the course of two days to collaboratively work with web collections and explore cutting-edge research tools through hands-on experience.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Publications</title>
      <link>https://archivesunleashed.org/publications/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Mar 2019 14:45:14 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://archivesunleashed.org/publications/</guid>
      <description>The Archives Unleashed project has a body of published research. Check back for more soon!
Journal Articles  Jimmy Lin, Ian Milligan, Jeremy Wiebe, and Alice Zhou. “Warcbase : Scalable Analytics Infrastructure for Exploring Web Archives.” ACM Journal of Computing and Cultural Heritage, Vol. 10, Issue 4, July 2017. [link] Ian Milligan, Nick Ruest, and Anna St.Onge. &amp;ldquo;The Great WARC Adventure : Using SIPS, AIPS and DIPS to Document SLAAPs.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Digging into WARCs - Hands-On with the Archives Unleashed Toolkit</title>
      <link>https://archivesunleashed.org/aut/resaw/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 May 2019 11:51:41 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://archivesunleashed.org/aut/resaw/</guid>
      <description>Workshop Description Welcome to &amp;ldquo;Digging into WARCs: Hands-On with the Archives Unleashed Toolkit.&amp;rdquo; The Archives Unleashed Toolkit, or AUT, is an open-source platform for managing and analyzing web archives built on Apache Spark.
This is a hands-on introductory workshop with the Archives Unleashed Toolkit and Archives Unleashed Jupyter Notebooks. No existing technical knowledge is needed, and we will be aiming this at beginner and intermediate users alike.
This workshop is being held on Tuesday, June 18th from 14:00-17:30 in room BG2 0.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Archives Unleashed Datathon Cheat Sheet</title>
      <link>https://archivesunleashed.org/aut/datathon/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Jan 2019 11:51:41 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://archivesunleashed.org/aut/datathon/</guid>
      <description>This guide is meant to be a quick reference guide for attendees at the Archives Unleashed datathons. These are commonly-asked questions and options that attendees have used, and may be updated during events.
Screenshots are from Mac, as we don&amp;rsquo;t have a Windows machine on our project team. Our apologies.
Finding Your Terminal While the Archives Unleashed Cloud is easy to use in a web browser, the Archives Unleashed Toolkit requires the use of the command line.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hands on With The Archives Unleashed Toolkit</title>
      <link>https://archivesunleashed.org/aut/docker-install/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Sep 2018 11:51:41 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://archivesunleashed.org/aut/docker-install/</guid>
      <description>This quick guide will walk through how to install Docker for Mac users. Much of this is also applicable to Windows users, although the screenshots are from a Mac.
Resources  Docker Community Edition for Mac Docker Community Edition for Windows  Install Docker To install Docker for a Mac OS, use this link. You can also use these instructions to install Docker on a Windows 10 Professional installation, by using this link.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hands on With The Archives Unleashed Toolkit</title>
      <link>https://archivesunleashed.org/aut/lesson/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 May 2018 11:51:41 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://archivesunleashed.org/aut/lesson/</guid>
      <description>Welcome to the Archives Unleashed Toolkit hands-on walkthrough!
The reality of any hands-on workshop is that things will break. We&amp;rsquo;ve tried our best to provide a robust environment that can let you walk through the basics of the Archives Unleashed Toolkit alongside us.
If you have any questions, let Nick Ruest or Ian Milligan know.
Table of Contents  Installation and Use Hello World: Our First Script Extracting Some Text  Ouch!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Toronto Datathon</title>
      <link>https://archivesunleashed.org/toronto/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Dec 2017 15:20:57 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://archivesunleashed.org/toronto/</guid>
      <description>About The World Wide Web has a profound impact on how we research and understand the past. The sheer amount of cultural information that is generated and, crucially, preserved every day in electronic form, presents exciting new opportunities for researchers. Much of this information is captured within web archives.
Web archives often contain hundreds of billions of web pages, ranging from individual homepages and social media posts, to institutional websites.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>